

### **SKILLS**

#### **Website Development**

React
Next JS
Javascript
Typescript
HTML
CSS
Nodejs
MongoDB
GraphQL
MySQL
Redux
Context API

#### **Others**

React Native
Docker
Java
C++
Python
Office Tools

### CONTACT

- ☆ Sargodha, Pakistan
- **\** +923029531121
- ✓ workwithusamabilal@gmail.com
- http://usamabilal.me/
- **○** CodeWUsama
- in www.linkedin.com/in/usamabilal-a08504173/

# **USAMA BILAL**

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPER (REACT JS | NEXT JS)

### **INTRODUCTION & EXPERTISE**

A passionate software engineer graduated from COMSATS who loves to code & create wonders in IT industry. My expertise are in web development particularly in frontend using React & Next JS. I also have working experience in React Native, Node JS & MongoDB. I am an analytical thinker and enjoy breaking down complex problems into manageable components and leading the team front the front to success.

### **EXPERIENCE**

June 2022 - Pres Devsinc

ent Software Engineer (React JS)

Leading the frontend team of US based referral

platfrom using React & Next js

OCTOBER Pakistan Airforce Headquaters

2021 - May 2022 Software Engineer (MERN)

Worked as a software engineer on two major software solutions for defense using MERN

stack.

June 2021 - Embrace IT

September 2021 Junior Frontend Engineer

Worked on the frontend of HRMS application

using React JS

#### HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

2022 - Present EMPLOYEE REFERRAL HIRING PLATFORM

US based project through Devsinc

Leading the frontend team for automated and

engaging employee referral platform.

2022 **DIGITAL WALLET** 

Freelance

Digital wallet managment app build in React

Native, Node JS & MongoDB.

WORKSPACE 2021

Embrace IT inhouse product

Company management platform to post jobs, manage candidates, conduct interviews and project meetings & manage employees finances.

2020-2021 WEBSITE CREATOR USING PRESETS

FYP for Comsats University Islamabad

Final Year Project- A platform build in MERN stack for a laymen to modify the provided templates and

publish websites.

### **EDUCATION**

**2017 - 2021** 

**BS Computer Science** 

COMSATS University, Islamabad CGPA: 3.74 (Gold Medalist)

2015 - 2017

**F.Sc. Pre-Engineering** Army College, Sargodha

Marks: 85%

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Batch Top Position Holder - Gold Medalist**

First position in the computer science department for batch 2017-2021 in COMSATS

#### **RISE IQ Test winner 2016**

Awarded with the second position for entry test classes conducted by RISE Sargodha

### **INTERESTS AND HOBBIES**

Logic Building
Logic building for custom algorithms

#### **Problem Solving**

- I enjoy analyzing complex issues, identifying key factors, and developing a clear plan of action to tackle the problem.
- Book Reading
   To enhance language skills and to develop thoughts

# **INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

- Project Management
- Leadership
- Team Player
- Time Management

# CONTACT

- ★ Sargodha, Pakistan
- **\** +923029531121
- ✓ workwithusamabilal@gmail.com
- http://usamabilal.me/
- in www.linkedin.com/in/usama-bilal-a08504173/
- CodeWUsama